Guide to the Oscar I. Norwich Collection of Maps of Africa and Its Islands, 1486 - ca. 1865 NORWICH
David Rumsey Map Center
Oscar I. Norwich collection of map of Africa and its islands
1486 - circa 1865
David Rumsey Map Center
Norwich, Rose
Norwich, I.
NORWICH
316 item(s): 316 maps
The collection contains 316 maps of Africa and its islands collected by Oscar I. Norwich.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
The collection contains 316 maps of Africa and its islands collected by Oscar I. Norwich, and include maps of Southern Africa; sea charts; the Cape of Good Hope; North, East, and West Africa; islands, ports, and town plans.
The majority of the maps are loose items, but a certain number are from rare, published atlases; a few were published in travel books.
Biography
Dr. I. Norwich of Johannesburg, South Africa, collected maps, both printed and manuscript, for more than thirty-five years.
Acquisition Information
Purchased in part with the support of the William R. & Yvonne E. Jacobson Africana Collections Program, 2002.
Access
Collection is open for research. All maps have been digitized and are available here: https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4719997
Africa -- History -- 19th century.; Africa -- History -- 17th century.; Africa -- History -- 18th century.; Africa -- History -- 16th century.; Norwich, Rose; Norwich, I.
- Quarta Affrice Tabula. = Map of Africa. -- Ulm: Leinhart Holle, Ulm (1482 edition); Johann Roger, Ulm (1486 edition); Germanus, Nicolaus, NOR 0001; Woodcut: Uncolored; 31 cm. x 47 cm.
  General note
  Program: Jacobson Africana Program
  Custodial History note
  Provenance: Dr. Oscar I. Norwich
  Source: Cosmographia (1482) (second edition)
  Descriptive Notes: Atlas based on Ptoleymy's Geographike Hyphegesis. Trapezoidal in projection. Based on Ptolemy's Geographike (about 120-150 AD), printed in Vicenza, Bologna, Florence, Rome and Ulm between 1475 and 1486. These Ptolomaic maps appeared after fall of Constantinople to the Ottoman Turks in 1453.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0001, p. 2
  Norwich number: 0001
  RID: MOA 0003
  Africa -- Africa -- 15th c.
- Africa, Libya, Morland, mit allen Kunigreichen so zu unsern zeiten darin gefunden werden. = Africa, Libya, Morland with their kingdoms to date. -- Basel: Munster, Sebastian, 1489-1552; Munster, Sebastian, 1489-1552, 1544-1545; NOR 0002; Woodcut: Uncolored; 26 cm. x 34 cm.
  Source: Cosmographia (second edition)
  Descriptive Notes: German edition. Map detailed with mountain ranges, rivers, and depictions of animals, a cyclops and crowns.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0002, p. 4
  Norwich number: 0002
  RID: MOA 0004
  Africa -- Africa -- 16th c.
- Totius Africae tabula et descriptio universalis etiam ultra Ptolemaei limites extensa. = Map of the whole of Africa based on Ptolemaic sources. -- Basel: Munster, Sebastian, 1489-1552; Munster, Sebastian, 1489-1552, 1542; NOR 0003; Woodcut: Colored; 26 cm. x 34 cm.
  Source: Geographia Universalis (1540-1542) (Latin edition)
  Descriptive Notes: Latin edition of Munster's map, see NOR 0002. Includes three places printed upside down: Quiloa, Mantes and Regnu[m].
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0003, p. 6
  Norwich number: 0003
  RID: MOA 0005
- Figura del Mondo Universale. = World map. -- Basel: Munster, Sebastian, 1489-1552; Munster, Sebastian, 1489-1552; Munster, Sebastian, 1489-1552; Kandel, David, 1524-1596, 1550; NOR 0004; : Colored; 25 cm. x 37 cm.
  Source: Cosmographia (1550)
  Descriptive Notes: Latin edition of Munster's map. Round-shaped world map surrounded by the heads of wind gods, blowing their winds towards the earth. Several sea monsters occupy the waters.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0004, p. 7
  Norwich number: 0004
  RID: MOA 0006
- La description d'Affricque selon les divers pais, animaux et monstres horribles. = A description of Africa showing the different countries, animals and monsters. -- Basel: Munster, Sebastian, 1489-1552; Munster, Sebastian, 1489-1552, 1550; NOR 0005; Woodcut: Colored; 12.4 cm. x 15.5 cm.
  Source: Cosmographia (1550) (French edition)
  Descriptive Notes: Top of map: Universelle, livre VI Le Sixiesme Livre de la Cosmographie, recueilly par Sebastian Munstere des bons autheurs tant anciens que moderuer, assemble.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0005, p. 8
  Norwich number: 0005
  RID: MOA 0007
- Prima Tavola. = [Africa] -- Venice: Ramusio, Giovanni Battista, 1485-1557; Ramusio, Giovanni Battista, 1485-1557; Ramusio, Giovanni Battista, 1485-1557, 1550; NOR 0006; Copperplate: Uncolored; 27 cm. x 38 cm.
  Source:
  Descriptive Notes: The original version of this map was executed as a woodcut in Delle Navigatione et Viaggi nel qual si contiene les descrittione dele Africa. South at top of map. Sea is engraved in horizontal wavy lines with several ships and sea monsters.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0006, p. 9
  Norwich number: 0006
  RID: MOA 0008
- Il disegno della geografia moderna de tutta la parte dell'Africa ... -- Venice: Gastaldi, Giacomo, c. 1500-1565; Gastaldi, Giacomo, c. 1500-1565; Gastaldi, Giacomo, c. 1500-1565, 1564; NOR 0008; Copperplate: Uncolored; 53 cm. x 142 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Rare separate map printed on eight copperplates. The sea is stippled with many ships and sea monsters.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0008, p. 11
  Norwich number: 0008
  RID: MOA 0010
- Africa a veteribus. -- Venice: Forlani, Paolo, 1562; NOR 0009a; : Uncolored; x
  Descriptive Notes: There are sea monsters and ships in the Atlantic and Indian Oceans and, to the North of the island of Madagascar, Noah's Ark is depicted, showing the dove returning with an olive branch in its beak.
  References: Not in Norwich Page number:PROBLEM 3/14/02
  Norwich number: 0009a
  RID: MOA 0011
- Presbiteri Johannis, Sive Abissinorum Imperii Descriptio. = The land of Prester John. -- Antwerp: Ortelius, Abraham, 1527-1598; Ortelius, Abraham, 1527-1598, 1573; NOR 0011; : Uncolored; 37 cm. x 43 cm.
  Source: Theatrum Orbis Terrarum
  Descriptive Notes: Map often referred to as the Prester John map, first issued in Additamentum. Dedicated to biblical David. An Arab dhow appears off the west coast. In the seas, two dolphins and on land four elephants; Map depicts Africa from the Mediterranean to the Mountains of the Moon.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0011, p. 16
  Norwich number: 0011
  RID: MOA 0013
- Table d'Afrique. = Map of Africa. -- Paris: Thevet, Andre, 1502-1590; Thevet, Andre, 1502-1590, 1575; NOR 0012; : Uncolored; 35 cm. x 44 cm.
  Source: Cosmographie Universelle (1575)
  Descriptive Notes: The sea is engraved in horizontal wavy lines which almost overpowers the outline of the continent. The seas contain numerous sailing vessels and sea monsters.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0012, p. 18
  Norwich number: 0012
  RID: MOA 0014
- Affricae Tabula Nova. = New map of Africa. -- Basel Munster, Sebastian, 1489-1552, 1580; NOR 0014; : Colored; 31 cm. x 36 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Based on Abraham Ortelius' maps. The coastline is jagged, and the geography is slightly fictitious. The seas contain two small sailing vessels and one sea monster. The top reads: Africa, Libya, Dozenlandt mit allen koinigreichen ...
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0014, p. 20
  Norwich number: 0014
  RID: MOA 0016
- [Depicts Africa from the Mediterranean to The Cape, excluding West Africa] -- Rome: Pigafetta, Filippo, 1533-1604; Pigafetta, Filippo, 1533-1604; Pigafetta, Filippo, 1533-1604, 1591; NOR 0016; : Uncolored; 62 cm. x 43 cm.
  Source: Relatione del reame di Congo et delle circonvicine contrade (1591)
  Descriptive Notes: Pigafetta's depiction of the origin of the Nile is an important landmark in the historical cartography of the Nile water basin, completely changing the traditional Ptolemaic concept. Dedicated to Antonio Miglioni Vescovo S. Marco.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0016, p. 23
  Norwich number: 0016
  RID: MOA 0018
- Africa Tertia Pars Terrae. = Africa the third continent. -- Hanover: Bunting, Heinrich, 1545-1606; Bunting, Heinrich, 1545-1606, 1592; NOR 0017; Woodcut: Uncolored; 26 cm. x 34 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Appeared in the first edition of Itinerarum Saccrae Scripturae (1581). This map has an unusual shape, tapering to a narrow angle in the south. The sea is engraved in vertical, wavy lines, with a galleon, a merman and a sea-bird.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0017, p. 25
  Norwich number: 0017
  RID: MOA 0019
- Die eigentliche und warhafftige gestalt der Erden und des Meers: Cosmographia Universalis. = The true shape of the world and the oceans. -- Hanover: Bunting, Heinrich, 1545-1606; Bunting, Heinrich, 1545-1606, 1592; NOR 0018; Woodcut: Uncolored; 27 cm. x 36 cm.
  Source: Itinerarum Saccrae Scripturae
  Descriptive Notes: "Jerusalem is sited in the centre of the map since it was regarded then as the centre of the world." Portion of America appears, Die Newe Wellt. The sea contains four sea monsters. Top left: 8. Top right: 9.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0018, p. 26
  Norwich number: 0018
  RID: MOA 0020
- Africae Vera Forma, et Situs. = The true shape and situation of Africa. -- Antwerp: Jode, Cornelis de, 1568-1600; Jode, Gerard de, 1509-1591; Jode, Gerard de, 1509-1591, 1593; NOR 0019; : Uncolored; 32 cm. x 45 cm.
  Source: Speculum Orbis Terrarum (second edition)
  Descriptive Notes: The seas contain sea monsters and sailing ships. Natives are seen on and around the map.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0019, p. 27
  Norwich number: 0019
  RID: MOA 0021
- Aphrica. = Africa. -- Cologne: Bussemacher, Johann, fl. 1580-1613; Bussemacher, Johann, fl. 1580-1613, 1600; NOR 0020; : Colored; 21 cm. x 29 cm.
  Source: Matthias Quad's Geographisch handtbuch ... (1600)
  Descriptive Notes: German text on verso mentions the work of Leo Africanus. Also states of Da Gama's voyage and the fact that the inhabitants are black.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0020, p. 28
  Norwich number: 0020
  RID: MOA 0022
- Africa. Ex magna orbis terre discriptione Gerardis Mercatoris desumpta. = Africa. Taken from the world atlas of ... -- Duisburg: Mercator, Gerhard, 1512-1594; Mercator, Gerhard, 1512-1594, 1595; NOR 0021; : Colored; 38 cm. x 46 cm.
  Source: Atlas sive, Cosmographicae meditationes de fabrica mundi et fabricati figura (1595)
  Descriptive Notes: Atlas first published in 1569. Map issued in several editions and in many languages. Includes Latin text on back of map. The cartouche is circular, surrounded by decorative scrolls and two satyrs.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0021, p. 29
  Norwich number: 0021
  RID: MOA 0046
- Africa. -- London: Wolfe, John, d. 1601; Pigafetta, Filippo, 1533-1604; Pigafetta, Filippo, 1533-1604, 1597; NOR 0023; : Uncolored; 62 cm. x 43 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: English edition, copied from the original Italian edition of 1591 (see map NOR 0016). Also appeared in Linschoten's His Discours of Voyages to the East and West Indies (1598). The sea is stippled and contains several ships and sea monsters.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0023, p. 31
  Norwich number: 0023
  RID: MOA 0047
- Africa. -- Venice: Porro, Girolamo, 1520-1604; Porro, Girolamo, 1520-1604; Porro, Girolamo, 1520-1604, 1598; NOR 0024; : Colored; 12.5 cm. x 17 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Based on Abraham Ortelius. Various editions of this map appeared between 1596 to 1620. Includes bulge of eastern Brazil down to the mouth of Rio de la Plata.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0024, p. 32
  Norwich number: 0024
  RID: MOA 0048
- Africa. -- Spain: Solis, Hermando de; Solis, Hermando de, 1598; NOR 0025; : Uncolored; 36.5 cm. x 50 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Similar to Abraham Ortelius map of Africa. Includes a scroll-type cartouche, with a lion's head on the lower border. Sea monsters and sailing vessels occupy the stippled sea.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0025, p. 33
  Norwich number: 0025
  RID: MOA 0024
- Africa. -- Siena: Arnoldi, Arnoldo de, d. 1602; Arnoldi, Arnoldo de, d. 1602, 1600; NOR 0026; Copperplate: Uncolored; 37 cm. x 48 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Another map that resembles the shape of Orlelius. The outline of the oval-shaped cartouche is scrollwork with floral ornamentation. The sea is stippled and contains three ships and two sea monsters.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0026, p. 34
  Norwich number: 0026
  RID: MOA 0025
  Africa -- Africa -- 17th c.
- Nova Africae Tabula. = New map of Africa. -- Amsterdam: Hondius, Jodocus, 1563-1612; Hondius, Jodocus, 1563-1612, 1606; NOR 0027; : Uncolored; 37 cm. x 50 cm.
  Source: Mercator's Atlas (1606)
  Descriptive Notes: Mercator based map with corrections and additions by Hondius. Four sailing vessels and three sea monsters decorate the seas.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0027, p. 36
  Norwich number: 0027
  RID: MOA 0049
- Tabula Geograph in qua Europe, Africae, Asia et circu ... = Map of Europe, Africa and Asia. -- Amsterdam Pontanus, Johannes Isacius, 1571-1639; Pontanus, Johannes Isacius, 1571-1639, 1611; NOR 0028; : Uncolored; 27 cm. x 42 cm.
  Source: Rerum et Urbis Amstelodamensium Historia ...
  Descriptive Notes: The map includes the Middle East, India, and China. Inset illustrates natives in traditional dress.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0028, p. 38
  Norwich number: 0028
  RID: MOA 0026
- Africae nova Tabula. = New map of Africa. -- Amsterdam: Hondius, Jodocus; Hondius, Jodocus, 1623; NOR 0029; : Colored; 45.5 cm. x 56.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Border illustrates views of towns and natives in traditional dress. Two Dutch ships are shown in the Atlantic Ocean, with flying fish and sea monsters.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0029, p. 39
  Norwich number: 0029
  RID: MOA 0050
- Africae, described, the manners of their Habits, and buildinge: ... -- London: Humble, George, d. 1640; Speed, John, 1552?-1629; Speed, John, 1552?-1629, 1626; NOR 0030; : Colored; 38 cm. x 50 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The borders show natives in traditional dress and views of towns.The seas contain flying fish and spouting whales. Elephants, lions, camels, monkeys and ostriches are shown on the mainland. The interior contains rivers, mountains, and lakes, many of which are fictitious. Description of Africa on verso.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0030, p. 40
  Norwich number: 0030
  RID: MOA 0051
- Africae novo descriptio. = New map of Africa. -- Amsterdam: Blaeu, Willem Janszoon ,1571-1638; Blaeu, Willem Janszoon, 1571-1638, 1630; NOR 0032; : Outline color; 40 cm. x 55 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Due to its popularity, this map was reprinted many times between 1631 to 1667. Similar features are found on Speed's map (see NOR 0030) and Hondius' map (see NOR 0029).
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0032, p. 42
  Norwich number: 0032
  RID: MOA 0053
- Nova descriptio Africae. = New map of Africa. -- Frankfurt: Merian, Matthaeus, 1593-1650; Merian, Matthaeus, 1593-1650; Merian, Matthaeus, 1593-1650, 1637; NOR 0033; : Uncolored; 26 cm. x 36 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Smaller version of Blaeu's map (see NOR 0032), but lacking borders.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0033, p. 42
  Norwich number: 0033
  RID: MOA 0027
- Africae nova tabula. = New map of Africa. -- Amsterdam: Jansonium, Joannem; Hondius, Hendrik, 1597-1651; Hondius, Hendrik, 1597-1651, 1641; NOR 0034; : Colored; 38 cm. x 50 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Latin text on verso. Re-issue of Jodocus Hondius' map (see NOR 0029), without the borders. Ships, Flying fish, sea monsters and a mermaid riding the waves decorate the seas. "The very full geographical description of Africa is typical of the seventeenth century, and is similar to that of Speed and Bleau."
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0034, p. 44
  Norwich number: 0034
  RID: MOA 0055
- Africa vetus. = Africa in antiquity ... -- Paris: Sanson, Nicolas, 1600-1667; Sanson, Nicolas, 1600-1667; Sanson, Nicolas, 1600-1667, 1650; NOR 0035; : Outline color; 39 cm. x 55 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The cartouche is composed of two eagles. The lower part consists of leaves and fruit. Southern part of Africa indicates that the "inhabitants are 'Anthropophagi Aethiopes' or cannibals."
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0035, p. 45
  Norwich number: 0035
  RID: MOA 0056
- Africae Descriptio Nova Impensis. = Latest description of Africa. -- London: Seile, Henry, d. ca. 1661; Seile, Henry, d. ca. 1661; Seile, Henry, d. ca. 1661, 1652; NOR 0036; : Colored; 34 cm. x 43 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Similar to Chetwind's map (see NOR 0039). The ocean is decorated with ships, flying fish and sea monsters. Elephants, lions, ostriches, and giraffes are illustrated on the mainland. "The River Niger is erroneously mapped and there are many ficticious lakes in Central Africa."
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0036, p. 46
  Norwich number: 0036
  RID: MOA 0057
- L'Afrique. = Africa. -- Paris: Duval, P (Pierre), 1619-1682; Duval, P (Pierre), 1619-1682; Duval, P (Pierre), 1619-1682, 1664; NOR 0038; : Outline color; 40 cm. x 53 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Re-issued in 1684. "The general shape of Africa is squat because it has been drawn somewhat wider from east to west than usual." Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0038, p. 48
  Norwich number: 0038
  RID: MOA 0059
- Africae Deseriptio Nova Impensis. = Latest description of Africa. --: Chetwind, Philip; Chetwind, Philip; Chetwind, Philip, 1666; NOR 0039; : Colored; 33 cm. x 43 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Similar to Seile's map (see NOR 0036). Several present day names of bays can be identified.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0039, p. 49
  Norwich number: 0039
  RID: MOA 0060
- A new and most exact map of Africa described by N.I. Vischer and don into English; Enlarged and Corrected according to J. Blaeu and Others, With the Habits of ye people, and ye manner of ye Cheife sitties ye like never before. -- London: Overton, John, 1640-1708?; Overton, John, 1640-1708?; Overton, John, 1640-1708?, 1666; NOR 0040; : Colored; 42 cm. x 51 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Similar to Blaeu's map (see NOR 0030). The sea is decorated with more ships than usual for "maps of this period and the sea monsters are fewer and smaller."
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0040, p. 50
  Norwich number: 0040
  RID: MOA 0061
- Africa Vetus, Nicolai Sanson Christianis Galliar Regis Geographi Recognita Emendata et Multis in locis Mutata, Conatibus Geographicis Gulielmi Sanson N. Filii. = Africa in antiquity. -- Paris: Sanson, Nicolas, 1600-1667; Sanson, Nicolas, 1600-1667, NOR 0041; : Colored; 40 cm. x 56 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The continent is misshaped, containing numerous coastal inlets. "All the inhabitants of southern Africa are labeled 'Anthropophagi Aethiopes' or cannibals."
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0041, p. 51
  Norwich number: 0041
  RID: MOA 0062
- A new Map of Africa Designed by Mounsir Sanson, Geographer to the French King. Rendered into English and Illustrated with Figurs by ... by the Kings Especiall Command. -- London: Blome, Richard, d. 1705; Blome, Richard, d. 1705; Blome, Richard, d. 1705, 1669; NOR 0042; : Outline color; 39 cm. x 54 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Similar to Sanson's map (see NOR 0035). Blome added ships, sea monsters and the dedication to the Right Honourable Charles Howard.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0042, p. 52
  Norwich number: 0042
  RID: MOA 0063
- Africae Accurata Tabula. = Accurate map of Africa. -- Amsterdam: Meurs, Jacob van, 1619-1680; Meurs, Jacob van, 1619-1680, 1670; NOR 0043; : Colored; 43 cm. x 54 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Similar to Visscher's map (see NOR 0055). Map was issued several times, in Dutch, French and German in Dapper's Africa. Blank shield in cartouche at lower left of map. Prime meridian through Tenerif.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0043, p. 53
  Norwich number: 0043
  RID: MOA 0064
- A Mapp of the Higher and Lower Aethiopia. Comprehending Ye Several Kingdomes c. in Each, to Witt, in the Empire of the Abissines, the Coast of Zanguebar, Abex, and Aian, with the Kingdomes of Nubia, and Biafra c. In the Lower Aethiopia the Kingdome of Congo, Ye Empire of Monomotapa and Monoemugy, Ye Coast and Lands of Cafres and of this Side Cape Negres with the Isles Madagascar c. -- Unknown Sanson, Nicholas, 1600-1667, No date; NOR 0044; : Colored; 30 cm. x 40 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The cartouche is almost identical to another Sanson's map (see NOR 0158). Dedicated to Sir William Glynne.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0044, p. 54
  Norwich number: 0044
  RID: MOA 0065
- Africa ... sic describente. = Africa described. -- Rome: Nicolosio, Joanne Baptista, 1610-1670; Nicolosio, Joanne Baptista, 1610-1670, 1671; NOR 0045; : Colored; 38 cm. x 44 cm.
  Source: Hercules siculus sive studium Geographicum (second edition)
  Descriptive Notes: Four-sheet folio map. Atlas first issued in 1660. "The map appears upside down, as was the custom with other Italian cartographers."
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0045, p. 55
  Norwich number: 0045
  RID: MOA 0066
- L'Afrique divisee suivant l'estendue de ses principales parties ou sont distingues les uns des autres, les Empires, Monarchies, Royaumes, Estats et Peuples qui partagent aujourd'huy l'Afrique sur les Relations les plus Nouvelles par le Sanson. = Africa divided into its principal parts ... -- Paris: Jaillot, Alexis Hubert, 1632?-1712; Jaillot, Alexis Hubert, 1632?-1712; Jaillot, Alexis Hubert, 1632?-1712, 1674; NOR 0046; : Colored; 54 cm. x 88 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: First edition of map.Title across top, L'Afrique distinguee en ses principales parties scavoir la Barbarie, le Biledulgerid, L'Egypte, le Saara ou le Desert, le Pays des Negres, la Guinee, La Nubie, L'Abissinie, le Zanguebar; le Congo, le Monomotapa, Les Cafres, Les Isles de Canaries, du Cap-Verd, de S. Thomas, L'sle Dauphine autrement Madagascar ... Tire sur les Relations les plus novelles Par le Sanson. Dedicated to monseigneur Ie Dauphin.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0046, p. 56
  Norwich number: 0046
  RID: MOA 0067
- Africa divided according to the extent of its Principall Parts in which are distinquished one from the other Empires, Monarchies, Kingdoms, States and Peoples which at this time inhabite Africa. -- London: Berry, William, fl. 1669-1708; Berry, William, fl. 1669-1708, 1680; NOR 0047; : Colored; 54 cm. x 89 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Based on Jaillot's map, (see NOR 0046). Title across top, Africa distinguished in its principal parts viz. Barbary. Biledulgerid, Egypt, Zaara or The Desert, the Country of the Negros, Guinea, Nubia, Abissinea, Zanguebar; Congo, Monomotapa, Caffrares, the Islands of the Canaries, Cape Verd, St. Thomas, Madagascar or St. Lawrence ... Described by Sanson. Corrected and amended by William Berry. Dedicated to Charles II; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0047, p. 58